<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Doria Keung</title>
    <link>https://doriable.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Doria Keung</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:20:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doriable.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 20:14:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Doria and I am a software developer working in infrastructure. I initially started my blog to share my experiences at a coding bootcamp back in 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 9: Projects Week 4</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/03/hackbright-week-9-projects-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:20:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/03/hackbright-week-9-projects-week-4/</guid>
      <description>The final full week of projects just flew past us and it&amp;rsquo;s been very stressful and exciting all at once! For those who don&amp;rsquo;t do well with suspense, I have figured out a way to stream music on the client-side (hurrah!). For those who have worked extensively with buffers, byte streams, Web Audio API and Python wave library are probably not all that impressed, but I am quite thrilled. There is now a bit of a wait time as the app processes the stream, but the client-side music playing is definitely worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 8: Projects Week 3</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/02/hackbright-week-8-projects-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 23:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/02/hackbright-week-8-projects-week-3/</guid>
      <description>This week felt slower and more frustrating than the other two weeks. Mostly because I felt like I invested a lot of time reading and going through documentation as I start hitting more complicated road blocks. Normally I would find this interesting and somewhat relaxing, but trying to go through large portions of complex materials quickly and efficiently in a limited amount of time was a little bit stressful. With that said, here are my stand-ups for Week 8:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 7: Projects Week 2</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/02/hackbright-week-7-projects-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 02:14:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/02/hackbright-week-7-projects-week-2/</guid>
      <description>This is my Week 7 (week 2 of projects) wrap-up, starting with daily scrum stand-ups:
 Monday: Over the weekend I worked on route for searching and rendering results from Spotify Web API. Today, I am working to create a route for adding songs that have been returned from the search. No blockers. Tuesday: Yesterday, I put together the route for searching and adding songs. Today, I am working on rendering the playlist based on the songs I&amp;rsquo;ve added and setting up WebSockets for real-time playlist rendering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 6: Projects Week 1</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/02/hackbright-week-6-projects-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/02/hackbright-week-6-projects-week-1/</guid>
      <description>My original plan was to blog each day of this week, updating everyone on my project progress. As I started writing posts each day of this week, I found myself writing things like &amp;ldquo;and then I scribbled lines on some graph paper to make wireframes. And then I did it again. And again&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. While each moment was a riveting learning experience in itself and I will look back fondly at my simple self in a few months time, the message really boiled down to &amp;ldquo;I did things that constituted working on my project&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 5</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/02/hackbright-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 23:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/02/hackbright-week-5/</guid>
      <description>Happy Lunar New Year! 🐵 Even though I was unable to celebrate it with my family in-person, I had the chance to Skype with them and wish them a happy new year.
It&amp;rsquo;s the end of week 5! Apologies on the late post this week, it&amp;rsquo;s been extremely hectic. We are about to start the second half of Hackbright: computer science topics and our personal projects, and I am both excited and anxious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 4</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/01/hackbright-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 01:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/01/hackbright-week-4/</guid>
      <description>As we cross the Week 4 finish line at Hackbright, we are also nearing the end of our metaphorical &amp;ldquo;80 days around the world of web development&amp;rdquo; (if only we actually got 80 days before we started our projects!).
This week was super exciting, although the contrast of SQL (which is awesome!) versus Javascript is a little bit of an emotional roller coaster for me. I have a working theory that Javascript is so widely-used because it popularized the mystique of programming and developers are trolls, thus wanting the general public to continue thinking that coding is &amp;ldquo;some magical shit that happens in a computer&amp;rdquo; without rhyme or reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 3</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/01/hackbright-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 02:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/01/hackbright-week-3/</guid>
      <description>Week 3 down and wowit was a crazy week! I&amp;rsquo;m fairly certain my brain is just liquid sloshing around in my skull right now and I&amp;rsquo;m afraid to go to sleep in case it starts pouring out of my ears. This week, we covered an incredibly broad range of topics:
 HTML and CSS (Geocities and Angelfire flashbacks — Hamster Dance, thisis all that&amp;rsquo;s left of you&amp;hellip;) How the web works (still tubes, wires, and magic — but also requests and responses!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 2</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/01/hackbright-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/01/hackbright-week-2/</guid>
      <description>Week 1 of Hackbright just wrapped up! Before digging into week 2 of Hackbright, I want to first observe a short moment of silence to honor the greatest head of house Slytherin has ever seen.
We covered a lot of ground this week at Hackbright, including the following:
 Collections: lists, tuples, sets, dictionaries Markov chains Twitter API Object-oriented programming More command line tools, including working with virtualenv  For me, week 2 had a real focus on expanding our understanding of developing software by bringing together all of these data structures and logical tools and getting our brains ticking on good &amp;ldquo;design&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackbright Week 1</title>
      <link>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/01/hackbright-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 23:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doriable.github.io/posts/2016/01/hackbright-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Week 1 of Hackbright just wrapped up!
Given that my first post was dedicated to my wonderful and supportive family and friends, this post is dedicated to the brilliant and fabulous Hack13right ladies I shared my first week with! It&amp;rsquo;s so interesting to see all the different backgrounds and unique personalities and it makes me more excited about the program by the day. We covered a lot of material in our first week, as well as some housekeeping stuff:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
